elektormagazine.com 2019-05-13

# Privacy Policy | Elektor Magazine

We are aware that you place your trust in us. We therefore see it as our responsibility to protect your privacy. On this page you can read which data we collect when you use Elektor International Media B.V.'s website and/or services, why we collect this data and how we improve your user experience with it. So you understand exactly how we work.

This page was last updated on May 24th 2018.

  We are aware that you place your trust in us. We therefore see it as our responsibility to protect your privacy. On this page you can read which data we collect when you use Elektor International Media B.V.'s website and/or services, why we collect this data and how we improve your user experience with it. So you understand exactly how we work.

  Elektor International Media B.V. respects the privacy of all users of its websites and ensures that the personal information you provide is treated confidentially. Elektor International Media B.V. acts in accordance with the Personal Data Protection Act and the General Data Protection Regulation from 25 May 2018.  
In the context of our services, we collect, store, pass on or otherwise process personal data. Under applicable privacy laws, we qualify as a data controller with respect to the personal data we process about you.  
Elektor International Media B.V. employees are obliged to respect the confidentiality of your data.

**1\. Who is Elektor International Media B.V.?**  
Elektor International Media B.V. is a private limited liability company with registered offices and place of business in Susteren and is registered with the Trade Register of the Chamber of Commerce under number 34249926 (KvK Limburg).

**2\. What personal data does Elektor International Media B.V. collect and process?**

 _Use of our services_

On Elektor International Media B.V.'s website you can see which services Elektor International Media B.V. offers and take out a suitable service.

  As part of our services, we collect personal data from our customers, visitors to our websites, subscribers, recipients of our newsletters, participants in conferences, events and training courses, participants in our online forums, persons who contact us by telephone, applicants and persons mentioned in our publications, websites and in our online database/guides.

  Depending on the service you purchase, we ask you to provide (personal) data, such as:

  Your details: 

  * gender;
  * full name and surname;
  * telephone number;
  * e-mail address;  
  * address information

Your company data (business customers): 

  * legal form;
  * company name;
  * address information;
  * e-mail address;
  * vat number;
  * Chamber of Commerce number

Payment details (if you order a product): 

  * IBAN and name.

Communication:  
When you send e-mails or other messages to us, for example using a form on the website, we retain those messages. Sometimes we ask you for your personal information that is relevant to the situation in question. This makes it possible to process your questions and answer your requests. The data is stored on Elektor International Media B.V.'s own secure servers or those of a third party.

 _Automatically generated data_

In order for the website to work optimally, automatically generated information about your use of the website is collected and processed. The optimisation of the service consists, among other things, of technical adjustments, for example, the correct display of pages and the security of the website.  
The information collected consists of the type of device (computer, mobile, tablet) you use, your IP address (number of your device that makes it possible to recognize your device), the type of browser, the operating system you use, and the pages you visit on the website as well as the items you view. In addition, we keep log-in data and selected values with the hostname that belongs to the IP address.

**3\. For what purposes and on the basis of what legal grounds is the information collected used?**

 _Purposes_

Your information will be used for the following purposes, and on the basis of the following legal grounds:

  The use is necessary for the execution: 

  * To make the use of the website possible;
  * To invoice you for the use of Elektor International Media B.V.'s services;

The processing is necessary for the representation of the legitimate interests of Elektor International Media B.V. 

  * To send you information about Elektor International Media B.V.'s own products and services and to respond to any questions and/or complaints you may have;
  * For compiling anonymised statistical data;
  * To secure, adapt and improve the website.

You have given your permission for the use or processing of data. This is necessary in order to comply with a legal obligation resting on Elektor International Media B.V., such as: 

  * To provide information about you to third parties if you have given your permission to do so or on the basis of legislation and/or regulations.

Elektor International Media B.V. wishes to keep you informed of the development of its services. If, for example, there is an expansion of the possibilities with the services, Elektor International Media B.V. will let you know. Elektor International Media B.V. can also keep you informed of actions that are and/or will be organised by Elektor International Media B.V. 

  If you do not wish to receive e-mail messages from Elektor International Media B.V., you can unsubscribe from e-mails sent by Elektor International Media B.V. at any time in almost every mail. In case you cannot or do not directly find such a link, you can also indicate your wishes by sending a message via [elektormagazine.com/unsubscribe](http://www.elektormagazine.com/unsubscribe).

 _Use by third parties_

If you provide personal data to Elektor International Media B.V. in connection with the services of Elektor International Media B.V., these personal data will not be shared with third parties, except and insofar as this is apparent from this privacy policy.

  Elektor International Media B.V. may provide your data to third parties insofar as you have explicitly indicated with regard to a specific third party that you give your consent to this and this is required in the context of your use of the services of Elektor International Media B.V. and/or insofar as this data cannot be traced back to you personally (such as automatically generated information, not being your IP or MAC address).  
Elektor International Media B.V. may, for example, engage third parties to outsource activities, such as service providers contracted by Elektor International Media B.V. (e.g. IT service providers or marketing agencies), mailing houses, owners/authors of products you buy from Elektor International Media B.V. or of documents you download from the Elektor International Media B.V. website, sponsors of conferences or events for which you register and advertisers. Elektor International Media B.V. also sometimes shares your personal data with its group companies.  
Elektor International Media B.V. does this in order to be able to make you tailor-made offers (or to have them made) and to bring you into contact with parties related to the subject. Elektor International Media B.V. bases the provision of your identification and contact details to these third parties on your permission. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You can do this by contacting [elektormagazine.com/my-privacy](http://www.elektormagazine.com/my-privacy).

  Elektor International Media B.V. only shares your personal data with third parties who are established in the European Economic Area (EEA). Occasionally outside, but only with parties who are 'GDPR-certified' by the competent institutions (Google, Mailchimp) or who are affiliated to the EU-US Privacy Shield. Elektor International Media B.V. ensures that, if applicable, appropriate measures are taken when it transfers your personal data to third parties. Elektor International Media B.V. will, for example, enter into a processing agreement where necessary (which sets out restrictions on the use of your personal data and obligations with regard to the security of your personal data).

  These third parties only process your personal data on behalf of Elektor International Media B.V. and for the benefit of (the purposes of) Elektor International Media B.V. Finally, Elektor International Media B.V. may provide your personal data to third parties if it is obliged to do so on the basis of legislation and/or regulations, if it is compelled to do so as a result of a lawsuit and/or in the event it deems this necessary in order to protect its own rights.

 _Ezine / Newsletter_

Elektor International Media B.V. has been working in accordance with the AVG / GDPR working method for years with regard to your registration for our ezines. Your registration is always explicit. We therefore ask you to confirm your registration and preferences once more. after yo subscribe You will then always have the possibility to register and unsubscribe by type of mail that we offer (editorial, commercial and partner). Unsubscribing and/or changing your preferences is possible at any time via the link 'GDPR Modify preferences' which is added at the bottom of each newsletter. 

 _Third party hyperlinks_

The website may contain hyperlinks by means of which you leave the environment of Elektor International Media B.V. and end up on the website of another party. Elektor International Media B.V. has no control over the services and/or websites of third parties to which links are provided. It is therefore possible that a different privacy statement applies to these services and/or websites of third parties.  
This privacy policy only applies to (personal) data that is processed by Elektor International Media B.V. Elektor International Media B.V. does not accept any responsibility or liability for (the operation and/or content of) services and/or websites of third parties.

**4\. How long does Elektor International Media B.V. store personal data?**  
Your personal data will be carefully stored and stored for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal data were collected and processed. Only if we are legally obliged to do so, or if this is necessary to defend our interests in legal proceedings (for example in the event of a dispute), will we retain personal data for longer periods of time.

**5\. Where are your personal data stored?**  
Your data is stored on Elektor International Media B.V.'s own secure servers or those of a third party. Elektor International Media B.V. uses servers in the Netherlands and Germany for the storage of personal data.

**6\. How is your personal information protected?**  
Elektor International Media B.V. has taken appropriate technical and organisational measures which, in view of the state of the art, are at all times sufficient to protect your personal data against loss or against any form of unlawful processing. For more information about how Elektor International Media B.V. sets up this security system, please contact us at [elektormagazine.com/it](http://www.elektormagazine.com/it).

**7\. Cookies**  
Elektor International Media B.V. uses cookies, fingerprints (or similar techniques) and social media plug-ins on its websites and mobile applications. Some of these are essential for the websites and mobile applications to work, others serve to provide you with a better, faster and safer user experience.  
Cookies are small information files that are stored on the hard disk of your computer or mobile device via your browser. For more information, please refer to the cookie statement [elektormagazine.com/cookies](https://www.elektormagazine.com/pages/cookie-statement). 

**8\. Accessing, improving and transferring your data?**  
If you want to see the information that has been recorded about you at Elektor International Media B.V., you can make a request for inspection. This request can be sent via [elektormagazine.com/my-privacy](http://www.elektormagazine.com/my-privacy).  
If you want to make changes to the data you have seen as a result of your sowing request, you can send a request to the appropriate employee. You can request Elektor International Media B.V. to modify, improve, supplement, remove or protect your data.   
You also have the right to obtain and transfer the personal data you provide in a common, structured and legible form. This request can also be sent via [elektormagazine.com/my-privacy](http://www.elektormagazine.com/my-privacy).

  Elektor International Media B.V. will respond to your request within one (1) month. In exceptional cases, Elektor International Media B.V. has the legal right to respond to your request within 3 months, for example if the request is very complex. Elektor International Media B.V. will let you know within 1 month.   
If Elektor International Media B.V. rejects your request, it shall state in its reply why the request to amend the data is rejected.

**9\. Can this privacy policy be changed?**  
This privacy statement may be amended. These changes will be published on this website and the latter date of change will be stated. We therefore advise you to consult this privacy statement on a regular basis.  

  **10\. Where can you complain?**  
If you have a complaint about the use of your personal data and you are unable to find a solution with Elektor International Media B.V., you can also submit your complaint to the authority for personal data, find yours [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).

  **11\. Questions and Feedback**  
Elektor International Media B.V. regularly checks whether it complies with this privacy policy. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us at [elektormagazine.com/my-privacy](http://www.elektormagazine.com/my-privacy) or send a letter to us:

  Elektor International Media B.V.  
attn. legal department  
P.O. Box 11  
6114 ZG Susteren
